<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> <channel><title>proxy social</title><item><title><![CDATA[Latinoware is not just for “nerds”]]></title><link>http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/185</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">For some time now the boundary between "nerds" and "the rest of us" is becoming increasingly blurred. To get an idea, the processing power of a typical cell phone today is higher than all the embarked capability on an Apollo spacecraft that took humans to the moon; vacuum cleaners and toys already run Linux and Linux and FreeBSD based systems, other free software feed the latest desktops, notebooks, netbooks, tablets, phones and everything else that is plugged into a power outlet.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp; <br />For some time now, the organization of Latinoware has sought to show that even people who understand nothing of computers, are already using free software and can help us make a positive difference in your neighborhood, society and the world, in many  different ways.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp; <br />If you enjoy communication, arts, musical production, check out the event schedule, which includes lectures on multimedia. We guarantee that you will not need to brush bits and bytes to model three-dimensional elements, create a movie or play at being a DJ.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp; </p>
<p><a href="http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/185" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[undefined]]></pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Education gains ground in Latinoware 2011]]></title><link>http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/183</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">As in other editions, this years Latinoware has once again prepared a special space dedicated to education. In addition to members of the Free Software in Education (<a href="http://sleducacional.org" title="http://sleducacional.org">http://sleducacional.org</a>) and their guests, the event also will feature the participation of groups from other Latin American countries, that will be discussing the integration between educators and users of free software throughout the continent. The main idea is to break down national and language borders in publicizing and providing support for the use of free software in education.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <br />On the last day of the event (21, Friday), the theme is highlighted at Latinoware on the  Education Trail. Check out the full schedule, and, below an interview with Frederico Guimaraes, a major champion of education on the Linux platform.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p>
<p><a href="http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/183" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[undefined]]></pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Plasma Active: KDE arrives at your tablet]]></title><link>http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/179</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">Recently, KDE introduced its newest technology: Plasma Active One, a new technology dedicated entirely to tablets, smartphones and touch-screen devices in general. Plasma Active One is a step further in the long journey of the KDE Plasma team, initially organized for the creation of a new shell desktop, since the projects beginning in 2007.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <br />Technology will be the theme of one of the lectures of Brazils KDE Forum IV - taking place during Latinoware 2011 - to be delivered by Sandro Andrade. With support for a number of devices based in Intel and ARM processors, Plasma Active One introduces the concept of Activities, specializes your medium to support touch-screen, and offers redesigned versions of the most popular applications. "This lecture presents the functional principles of Plasma Active, a general vision of its architecture, and the possibilities of contributing to the project", Sandro said.<br />&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; <br />Speakers - <a href="http://www.latinoware.org/pt-br/node/137"><strong>IV Fórum KDE Brasil</strong></a>.</p>]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[undefined]]></pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Serpro brand presence at Latinoware 2011]]></title><link>http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/175</link><description><![CDATA[<p><img src="/sites/default/files/Untitled-2-04_0.png" width="337" height="122" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">The Federal Data Processing Service (Serpro), the public information technology company of the Federal Government, is one of the sponsors of the Latin American Free Software Conference VIII (Latinoware) and will present its major projects based on free platforms from the 19th to the 21st of October.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp; <br />&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;"><strong>Demoiselle<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong></p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">On the first day, the 19th, Flávio Gomes Lisboa will initiate the company’s participation with the lecture “Benefiting from JEE6 with a free Brazilian framework”, which will take place at 12 at the Espaço Equador. The idea is to present the opportunities for improvements in Java development starting from the use of the latest version of the Demoiselle Framework, which is already prepared to utilize Java Enterprise Edition technology (JEE).</p>
<p><a href="http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/175" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[undefined]]></pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Your Latinoware!]]></title><link>http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/172</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;"><img src="/sites/default/files/euvou.png" width="500" height="146" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /><br />We are just days away from the beginning of Latinoware 2011 and, in case you still haven’t done it, now is the time to get the event program and plan your wanderings through the lectures, short courses, and other events taking place<br />between the 19 and 21 of October. Also, don’t forget to save some time for visiting the exposition area, the community stands, and, of course, to interact with the old and new friends that you will undoubtedly meet. <br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <br />As usual, those that are already accustomed to using Latinoware as a meeting point for their community will not be disappointed. The people of Python, PHP, Expresso, Gnome, KDE, Debian, OpenSUSE, Ubuntu, Mozilla and many other communities will be present. But also, be sure to look at that which seems to be outside your initial interests. Notice that, for example, on the Education Trail – a structuring trail of Latinoware – you will encounter talks that seem to have been “imported” from other communities.&nbsp; <br />&nbsp;&nbsp; </p>
<p><a href="http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/172" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[undefined]]></pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Relógio autografado por Linus Torvalds será sorteado por "Maddog" durante a Latinoware]]></title><link>http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/171</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">Os participantes da Latinoware que realizarão as provas de certificação do LPI (Linux Professional Institute) têm ainda mais um motivo para se animar com a proximidade do evento. O lendário Jon “Maddog” Hall anunciou que sorteará, entre os participantes da LPI II, um relógio de quartzo feito de CD-ROM e autografado por ninguém menos que Linus Tourvalds, o criador do Linux.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp; <br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/171" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[undefined]]></pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Desenvolvimento do LibreOffice se estende para o Brasil]]></title><link>http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/168</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;"><span style="font-family: Arial,sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">A formação do Núcleo de Desenvolvimento para o Software Livre, anunciada pela CIO da Itaipu Binacional, Marli Portella, durante a Latinoware 2010, já conta com toda a preparação necessária  para tornar-se realidade. Esse núcleo, que terá a sua sede em Foz do Iguaçu, contribuirá para o desenvolvimento da suíte de escritório LibreOffice e de outros projetos de software livre, por meio da formação de profissionais no Brasil.  A ação é  coordenada pela Itaipu Binacional, pela Fundação Parque Tecnológico Itaipu (FPTI) e pela a Associação Libre de Tecnologias Abertas (ALTA). </span></span></p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;"><span style="font-family: Arial,sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;"><br />O Núcleo de Desenvolvimento para o Software Livre colabora com a visão da The Document Foundation, mantenedora do software, que tem por objetivo fazer o LibreOffice um software livre independente de um único patrocinador corporativo. Essa iniciativa também reduzirá a dependência dos usuários brasileiros de desenvolvimento exclusivamente internacional e, com isso, contribuirá com código e recursos para a suíte de escritório livre que mais cresce no mundo.</span></span></p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/168" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[undefined]]></pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Últimos dias para participar do Caça Ideias Android ou Arduino]]></title><link>http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/167</link><description><![CDATA[<p><span style="color: #000000; font-size: small; font-family: arial,helvetica,sans-serif;"><em>Se sua ideia for a escolhida, a 4Linux ajudará você a criar um plano de negócios e apresentá-lo ao FINEP. Se o projeto for aprovado pela FINEP, a 4Linux oferece contrapartida de até R$300mil.</em></span></p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;"><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="font-family: Arial,sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">Você tem alguma aplicação, solução ou produto desenvolvido em Android ou Arduino publicado e precisa mostrar ao mercado? Sua solução está em produção mas precisa evoluir para ser um sucesso? A 4Linux quer ser sua parceira investindo até R$ 300.000,00 (trezentos mil reais) disponibilizando recursos humanos e técnicos e ajudá-lo a desenvolver um plano de negócios para submeter ao FINEP - Financiadora de Estudos e Projetos, empresa pública vinculada ao MCT (Ministério da Ciência e Tecnologia).</span></span></span></p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">&nbsp;</p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;"><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="font-family: Arial,sans-serif;"><span style="font-size: small;">Serão duas etapas. A primeira acontecerá entre os dias 19 e 21 de outubro de 2011 durante o evento Latinoware (VIII Conferência Latino-Americana de Software Livre) em Foz do Iguaçu/ PR, em que os diretores da 4Linux estarão “caçando ideias”. É o Caça Ideias ANDROID ou ARDUINO.</span></span></span></p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/167" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[undefined]]></pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Latinoware abre espaço para as comunidades]]></title><link>http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/165</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">Atendendo a uma sugestão de congressistas e membros de várias comunidades de Software Livre, a Latinoware deste ano irá oferecer um espaço diferente de atividades para as comunidades. Flexibilizando a programação oficial do evento, estes espaços permitirão que as comunidades organizem-se de maneira mais ágil e dinâmica, adequando as atividades de acordo com o desejo dos participantes até mesmo durante o evento.<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">Caso você seja membro ou simpatize com as comunidades Debian, OpenSUSE, Mozilla ou Ubuntu, ou queira participar de discussões mais aprofundadas e acaloradas envolvendo diversos assuntos, o espaço é uma boa oportunidade. Entre os temas abordados estarão saúde, tecnologias livres, modelos de negócios latinoamericanos e soluções disponibilizadas por meio do Portal Software Público Brasileiro. Confira o cronograma abaixo: <br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;"><strong>Quarta-feira (19)</strong><br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;"><em>ESPAÇO COLÔMBIA [Sala 6 – Verde]</em></p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">10h às 14h – 16h às 19h</p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">Espaço Ubuntu<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;"><em>ESPAÇO VENEZUELA [Sala 7 - Verde]</em></p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm;">10h às 14h – 16h às 19h</p>
<p><a href="http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/165" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[undefined]]></pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Robots produced in 3D printers and developed in open source code]]></title><link>http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/164</link><description><![CDATA[<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm; text-align: justify;"><img src="/sites/default/files/Oshw-miniskybot.jpg" width="378" height="289" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></p>
<p class="western" style="margin-bottom: 0cm; text-align: justify;">This year’s <strong>Latinoware</strong> is preparing many novelties for its participants. On the second day of the event (20), for example, Juan González-Gómez – a staunch champion of free software e hardware – will give a lecture on free robots that can be created using a 3D printer. We took advantage of trhe opportunity to talk to Gómez about other issues. <strong>Check it out!</strong><br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <br /><strong>1. Professor Juan, it is a great pleasure for us to have you in our conference. Latinoware began in 2004 as an event of Latin American integration through the use of free software. Then we learned that free software is just a small part of something much more important: free knowledge in all its manifestations. Today people accept more naturally freedom of information on intangibles, such as software and knowledge available on the web. But people like you are working with the technological freedom for something very tangible, like robots. Is it possible to make a reality in which all the necessary technology for the production of industrial robots free of patents, for example?<br />&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; </strong></p>
<p><a href="http://www.latinoware.org/en/node/164" target="_blank">read more</a></p>]]></description><pubDate><![CDATA[undefined]]></pubDate></item></channel></rss>